due-north.com 2017-12-16

# Spend Control and eProcurement solutions - PROACTIS

This Privacy Policy sets out how PROACTIS Holdings PLC (which includes PROACTIS and its subsidiary companies Due North, Millstream, Intelligent Capture, Perfect Commerce, Hubwoo, using the terms “PROACTIS”, "we", "us", "our") uses and protects any information that you ("you", "your") make available to us in connection with or when you use this website as well as the goods and services PROACTIS provides.

PROACTIS is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected and will only use your information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Notice is designed to cover the PROACTIS website ([proactis.com](http://www.proactis.com/)) and PROACTIS products. If there are any variations or specific elements unique to a PROACTIC product or service, that will be highlighted in its own section, later in this policy.

This Privacy Notice is available in the Welsh language. If you require this in Welsh, please click here. 

**1.  ** **What information do we collect?  
2. Information about website visits  
3. Using your personal data  
4. Social media platforms  
5. Shortened links in social media  
6. Third party websites  
7. Where we store your personal data  
8. Policy amendments  
9. Further information  
10\. PROACTIS products**  
**11. ProContract**  
**12. PROACTIS Central and Kayako Support (aka “Supplier Support”)**  
**13. Perfect Commerce**

**(1) What information do we collect?  

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data: 

**

**(a) information about your visits to and use of this website; (b) information about any transactions carried out between you and us on or in relation to this website; (c) information that you provide to us for the purpose of registering with us and/or subscribing to our website services and/or email notifications.

We may collect, store and use non-personal data about your visits to and use of this website.

**(2) Information about website visits**

**

**We may collect information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and number of page views.  ** **We may use this information in the administration of this website, to improve the website’s usability, and for marketing purposes.  

We use cookies on this website. For further details, see our Cookie Policy . If our products have additional uses for Cookies, that will be made clear through a dedicated Cookie Policy link on the individual product. 

**

**(3) Using your personal data**

**Personal data submitted on this website will be used for the purposes specified in this privacy policy or in relevant parts of the website. In addition to the uses identified elsewhere in this privacy policy, we may use your personal information to: **

  * **(a) improve your browsing experience by personalising the website;**
  * **(b) send information (other than marketing communications) to you which we think may be of interest to you by post, by email or similar technology;**
  * **(c) send to you marketing communications relating to our business which we think may be of interest to you by post or, where you have specifically agreed to this, by email or similar technology.**
  * **(d) provide other companies with statistical information about our users – but this information will not be used to identify any individual user.**

** Your personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use, as detailed in the Data Protection Act 1998. Every effort has been made to ensure that a safe and secure email submission process exists, however PROACTIS does advise those people who use such email forms that they do so at their own risk.**

**We may contact you from time to time to tell you about products or services, the same or similar to, those that you have enquired about or about other matters that we believe may be of interest to you.**  
  
**If you do not want us to contact you in this way, you can update your email preferences or opt-out by clicking the link at the borrom of received emails, write to us at PROACTIS, Riverview Court, 1 Castle Gate, Wetherby, LS22 6LE (marking your correspondence for the attention of The Marketing Team), or email[info@proactis.com](mailto:info@proactis.com).**

(4) Social media platforms

**This website may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question. Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion. Note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.

Users are advised to use social media platforms wisely and communicate / engage upon them with due care and caution in respect of their own privacy and personal details.

It is recommended that individuals’ security preferences are checked to ensure that each individual is happy with their own social media settings and if in any doubt, to review that social media’s own privacy notice and policies. PROACTIS cannot be held responsible for the consequences of individuals sharing items [be that links, pictures or other media] in a social network or other public forum.

**

**Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that this website and its owners participate  ** **on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.**

**Neither this website nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms.**

(5) Shortened links in social media

**This website and PROACTIS, through their social media platform accounts, may share web links to relevant web pages. By default, some social media platforms shorten lengthy URLs [web addresses] (this is an example:<http://goo.gl/duvQep>).

Users are advised to take caution and good judgement before clicking any shortened URLs published on social media platforms by this website and its owners. Despite the best efforts to ensure only genuine URLs are published, many social media platforms are prone to spam and hacking and therefore this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any shortened links.

**

(6) Third party websites  
  
**The website contains links to other websites. PROACTIS cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked websites. PROACTIS is not responsible for the privacy policies of third party websites. PROACTIS also recommends that users refer to those third-party websites’ privacy policies.**

(7) Where we store your personal data

**As a global company, the data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by PROACTIS staff operating outside the EEA within PROACTIS offices. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of the services you subscribe to, including the provision of support services.

In addition to the UK, PROACTIS has offices in the United States, Europe (such as France and Germany) and Australasia (such as New Zealand and Philippines) where support services can be carried out.

By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. PROACTIS will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers, which can be based in the EEA or outside of the EEA, dependent upon product or service involved. It may be necessary to store this data in a non-EEA secure server for a period of time should the main server be inoperable and whilst the main server issue is being resolved. If this occurs, PROACTIS customers will be informed through a specific communication which will include further details of that incident.

**

(8) Policy amendments  
**  
We may update this Privacy Policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes. If not, please contact the PROACTIS Data Protection Officer using the contact methods described below.**

(9) Further information

**For further information on how your information is used, how we maintain the security of your information and your rights to access information we hold on you, please contact:

By email: [compliance@proactis.com](mailto:compliance@proactis.com)

By post: The Data Protection Officer, PROACTIS Group Limited, Riverview Court, 1 Castle Gate, Wetherby, LS22 6LE  
  
For email messages, if you do not want us to contact you, you can amend your email preferences or opt-out by clicking on the link at the bottom of emails, write to us at the address shown above, marking your correspondence for 'The Marketing Team', or email [info@proactis.com](mailto:info@proactis.com).

**

(10) PROACTIS products

**PROACTIS products will typically require users to have a username and a password. The username may be a unique identifier or an email address. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

Any additional information required will be for the stated purposes for the application usage and not excessive.

PROACTIS Products will issue out system messages, to enable defined users to act upon processes that are necessary to fulfil the normal practices of the software (such as alerting an authoriser that they have invoices to approve or to alert a supplier that they have a deadline for a tender).

Whilst these are not marketing messages, users are able to change their preferences within product should they not wish to receive such notifications. By doing so, this may alter the functionality and lessen the effectiveness of the software.

**

(11) ProContract

The ProContract product operates an email newsletter program, which is used to inform subscribers about products and services supplied by PROACTIS. Users can subscribe through an online automated process, which is optional.

Some subscriptions may be manually processed through prior written agreement with the user.

Subscriptions are taken in compliance with UK Spam Laws, which are detailed in the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003.  
All personal details relating to subscriptions are held securely and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

No personal details are passed on to third parties, nor shared with companies / people outside of PROACTIS.

(12) PROACTIS Central and Kayako Support

**PROACTIS Central ([proactissupport.co.uk](http://www.proactissupport.co.uk/), [proactissupport.com](http://www.proactissupport.com/)) and Kayako Support ([proactis.kayako.com](http://proactis.kayako.com/default)) (which is also known as Supplier Support) are web-based applications, designed to allow registered users to raise support enquiries regarding the PROACTIS products and services.

Kayako is a third-party application and PROACTIS uses its’ software for Suppliers to log enquiries. It is recommended that you review their privacy policy ([kayako.com/about/privacy](https://www.kayako.com/about/privacy)) in addition to this, should you also use that support software.

As part of the registration process, and to fulfil the enquiries raised in the systems, the following personal data will be captured:

A person’s name, email address, telephone number, company or organisation that person works for, job role.

Whilst the nature of each enquiry is related to the products and services PROACTIS supplies, it is possible that users can add other information to the enquiry which may end up being other personal data, though this should only be for the purposes of resolving that particular enquiry.

To fulfil these enquiries for our customers, the PROACTIS staff who work on the enquiries may be based in any PROACTIS office, in addition to those based in the UK. PROACTIS has offices in the United States, Europe (such as France and Germany) and Australasia (such as New Zealand and Philippines) where support services can be carried out.

PROACTIS will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and has processes in place to help prevent unauthorised access to confidential information about you that is under our control.

For example, complying with internationally recognised standards such as ISO 27001 (more information is here: [iso.org/isoiec-27001-information-security.html](https://www.iso.org/isoiec-27001-information-security.html)).

The United States offices comply with the US-EU Privacy Shield Framework (more information about this is here: [privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/) and listed as Perfect Commerce here: [privacyshield.gov/list](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list)).

These safeguards help prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of Data.

**

(13) Perfect Commerce

**Whilst Perfect Commerce is a PROACTIS company, the Perfect Commerce suite of solutions is based out of the United States. To learn more about Perfect Commerce’s privacy notice, please follow this link:[perfect.com/terms-use-legal-information/privacy-policy](http://www.perfect.com/terms-use-legal-information/privacy-policy/). 

_Last Updated: September 2017_

**
